Blair and Lee Family Papers, 1640-1946 (bulk 1812-1920 ): Finding Aid C0614
Manuscripts Division
- Papers of Elizabeth Blair Lee, 1781-1913; 21 boxes
  - Correspondence, 1781-1905; 19 boxes
    - Other Family, 1781-1897; 9 boxes
      - Etting, Miriam Gratz: 2 ALsS, 1843-1876; 1 folder (Box 236, Folder 25)
      - Franklin, Marion: 3 ALsS, 1885; 1 folder (Box 236, Folder 26)
      - Gratz, Anna Maria Boswell (Mrs. Benjamin Gratz), 1809-1892: 5 ALsS, 1883-1885; 1 folder (Box 236, Folder 27)
      - Gratz, Benjamin (son of Henry H. Gratz), 1870-1883; 2 folders
        - Gratz, Benjamin, ALS, 1883; 1 folder (Box 236, Folder 28)
        - Gratz, Benjamin, ALS, 1870; 1 folder (Box 236, Folder 29)
      - Gratz, Henry Howard (1824-1913): 6 ALsS, 1877-1883; 1 folder (Box 236, Folder 30)
      - Gratz, Hermine: 5 ALsS, 1882-1890; 1 folder (Box 236, Folder 31)
      - Gratz, Laura Bodley: 5 ALsS, 1883-1891; 1 folder (Box 236, Folder 32)
      - Gratz, Maria Gist, first wife of Benjamin Gratz: 9 ALsS, 1833-1839; 1 folder (Box 236, Folder 33)
      - Gratz, Rebecca, sister of Benjamin Gratz, 1781-1869: 73 ALsS, 1840-1866; 2 ALsS, undated, to "Mary", 1 folder (Box 236, Folder 34)
      - Harrison, Alice J.: ALS, 1877; 1 folder (Box 236, Folder 35)
      - Harrison, Kate (Catherine): 15 ALsS, 1850-1870; ACsS, 1853; 1 folder (Box 236, Folder 36)
      - Harrison, Maria W.: 2 ALsS, 1877-1890; 1 folder (Box 236, Folder 37)
      - Harrison, Mary J.: ALS, 1877; 1 folder (Box 236, Folder 38)
      - Harrison, Sarah: ALS, 1892; 1 folder (Box 236, Folder 39)
      - Hart, E. L.: ALS, 1858; 1 folder (Box 236, Folder 40)
      - Hays, I. Minis (1847-1925): 3 ALsS, 1892; 1 folder (Box 236, Folder 41)
      - Hays, "Aunt": ALS, 1850; 1 folder (Box 236, Folder 42)
      - Hays, H. M.: ALS, 1885; 1 folder (Box 236, Folder 43)
      - Heap, Bessie Beal: 12 ALsS, 1889; 1 folder (Box 237, Folder 1)
      - Hensley, Kate: ACS, undated; 1 folder (Box 237, Folder 2)
      - Hidgson, Caroline O.: ALS, 1880; 1 folder (Box 237, Folder 3)
      - Howard, Nellie W.: 7 ALsS, 1880-1892; 1 folder (Box 237, Folder 4)
      - Joseph, Henry: 2 ALsS, 1881-1887; 1 folder (Box 237, Folder 5)
      - Joseph, J. H.: 16 ALsS, undated; 1 folder (Box 237, Folder 6)
      - Joseph, Sara, 1832-1892; 1 box 7 folders
        - Joseph, Sara, 1832-1836; 1 folder (Box 237, Folder 7)
        - Joseph, Sara, 1837-1839; 1 folder (Box 237, Folder 8)
        - Joseph, Sara, 1840-1841; 1 folder (Box 237, Folder 9)
        - Joseph, Sara, 1842-1843; 1 folder (Box 237, Folder 10)
        - Joseph, Sara, 1844-1846; 1 folder (Box 237, Folder 11)
        - Joseph, Sara, 1847-1850; 1 folder (Box 237, Folder 12)
        - Joseph, Sara, 1851-1855; 1 folder (Box 237, Folder 13)
        - Joseph, Sara, 1857-1867; 1 folder (Box 238, Folder 1)
        - Joseph, Sara, 1871-1878; 1 folder (Box 238, Folder 2)
        - Joseph, Sara, 1879-1881; 1 folder (Box 238, Folder 3)
        - Joseph, Sara, 1882-1883; 1 folder (Box 238, Folder 4)
        - Joseph, Sara, 1884-1886; 1 folder (Box 238, Folder 5)
        - Joseph, Sara, 1887-1889; 1 folder (Box 238, Folder 6)
        - Joseph, Sara, 1891-1892; 1 folder (Box 238, Folder 7)
      - Lee, Annie, 1850-1896; 1 folder (Box 239, Folder 1)
      - Lee, Arthur: ALS, 1883; 1 folder (Box 239, Folder 2)
      - Lee, Blair (1857-1944): 14 ALsS, 1873-1891; 2 telegrams, 1890; 1 folder (Box 239, Folder 3)
      - Lee, Ellen A. (Mrs. John F. Lee), 1839-1892; 3 folders
        - Lee, Ellen A. (Mrs. John F. Lee), 1839-1850; 1 folder (Box 239, Folder 4)
        - Lee, Ellen A. (Mrs. John F. Lee), ALS, 1851, to Samuel Phillips Lee, 1 folder (Box 239, Folder 5)
        - Lee, Ellen A. (Mrs. John F. Lee), 1880-1892; 1 folder (Box 239, Folder 6)
      - Lee, John F, 1843-1876; 1 folder (Box 239, Folder 7)
      - Lee, John F., Jr.: 3 ALsS, 1872; ACS, 1881; 1 folder (Box 239, Folder 8)
      - Lee, Sarah Little, 1839-1892; 1 folder (Box 239, Folder 9)
      - Lee, Samuel Phillips (1812-1897): condolence letters regarding his death, 1 folder (Box 239, Folder 10)
      - Lee, William Hall: ALS, 1871; 1 folder (Box 239, Folder 11)
      - Marshall, Thomas F.: 7 ALsS (fragments), 1842-1843; 1 folder (Box 240, Folder 1)
      - McKim, Anne Clymer, mother of Anne Clymer Brooke: 2 ALsS, 1891; 1 folder (Box 240, Folder 2)
      - Mordecai, Rose (1839-1936): 3 ALsS, 1883; ALS (signed "Rosa"), 1856; 1 folder (Box 240, Folder 3)
      - Mordecai, Sara, niece of Benjamin Gratz (1805-1894): 2 ALsS, 1858-1892; 1 folder (Box 240, Folder 4)
      - Moses, Horace, and Marian Moses, 1850-1892; 15 folders
        - Moses, Horace, 4 ALsS, 1850-1858; 1 folder (Box 240, Folder 5)
        - Moses, Horace, 29 ALsS, 1861-1868; 1 folder (Box 240, Folder 6)
        - Moses, Horace, 15 ALsS, 1871-1875; 1 folder (Box 240, Folder 7)
        - Moses, Horace, 1877-1888; 1 folder (Box 240, Folder 8)
        - Moses, Horace, and Marian Moses, 14 ALsS, 1879-1880; 1 folder (Box 240, Folder 9)
        - Moses, Horace, and Marian Moses, 1881-1883; 1 folder (Box 240, Folder 10)
        - Moses, Horace, and Marian Moses, 1884-1885; 1 folder (Box 240, Folder 11)
        - Moses, Horace, 1886; 1 folder (Box 240, Folder 12)
        - Moses, Horace, 1887; 1 folder (Box 240, Folder 13)
        - Moses, Horace, 1888; 1 folder (Box 240, Folder 14)
        - Moses, Horace, 1889; 1 folder (Box 241, Folder 1)
        - Moses, Horace, 1890; 1 folder (Box 241, Folder 2)
        - Moses, Horace, 1891; 1 folder (Box 241, Folder 3)
        - Moses, Horace, 1892; 1 folder (Box 241, Folder 4)
        - Moses, Horace, 3 ALsS, undated; 1 folder (Box 241, Folder 5)
      - Moses, Rebecca Gratz: ALS, undated; 1 folder (Box 241, Folder 6)
      - Moses, Sara, undated; 1 folder (Box 241, Folder 7)
      - Moses, Simon Gratz, 1813-1897: 3 ALsS, undated; 1 folder (Box 241, Folder 8)
      - Nicholas, Elizabeth Byrd: ALS, undated; 1 folder (Box 241, Folder 9)
      - Paterson, Lizzie: 4 ALsS, 1838; 5 ALsS to introduce E. B. L, undated; 1 folder (Box 241, Folder 10)
      - Pearson, Lizzie: ALS, undated; 1 folder (Box 241, Folder 11)
      - Reading, Fannie W.: ALS, 1883; 1 folder (Box 241, Folder 12)
      - Richey, Minna Blair (1850-1919), 1889-1892; 1 folder (Box 241, Folder 13)
      - Riggs, Francis B.: 10 ALsS, 1866-1892; 1 folder (Box 241, Folder 14)
      - Riggs, Janet M. C., undated; 1 folder (Box 241, Folder 15)
      - Riggs, Elisha, Jr.: 2 ALsS, 1851; 1 folder (Box 241, Folder 16)
      - Riggs, Mary, 1849-1888; 1 folder (Box 241, Folder 17)
      - Ringgola, T. L.: ALS, undated; 1 folder (Box 241, Folder 18)
      - Robinson, Arthur Lee: 2 ALsS, 1864; 1 folder (Box 241, Folder 19)
      - Robinson, Frances Lee (Mrs. Goldsborough Robinson), 1845-1888; 7 folders
        - Robinson, Frances Lee (Mrs. Goldsborough Robinson), 1845-1856; 1 folder (Box 241, Folder 20)
        - Robinson, Frances Lee (Mrs. Goldsborough Robinson), 1862-1879; 1 folder (Box 241, Folder 21)
        - Robinson, Frances Lee (Mrs. Goldsborough Robinson), 1881-1885; 1 folder (Box 242, Folder 1)
        - Robinson, Frances Lee (Mrs. Goldsborough Robinson), 1886; 1 folder (Box 242, Folder 2)
        - Robinson, Frances Lee (Mrs. Goldsborough Robinson), 1887-1888; 1 folder (Box 242, Folder 3)
        - Robinson, Frances Lee (Mrs. Goldsborough Robinson), undated; 2 folders (Box 242, Folder 4-5)
      - Robinson, Matilda Prather (Mrs. Goldsborough Robinson): 2 ALsS, 1890-1892; 1 folder (Box 242, Folder 6)
      - Pettit, William: 2 ALsS, 1850-1867; ALS, 1867, to his wife Frances Lee Robinson Pettit, 1 folder (Box 242, Folder 7)
      - Preston, M. W.: ALS, 1855; 1 folder (Box 242, Folder 8)
      - "Rose-bud": ALS, undated; 1 folder (Box 242, Folder 9)
      - Rult, Ida L.: ALS, undated; 1 folder (Box 242, Folder 10)
      - Stuart, Bella: ALS, undated; 1 folder (Box 242, Folder 11)
      - Washington, E. L.: ALS, undated; 1 folder (Box 242, Folder 12)
      - White, M. H.: ALS, 1883; 1 folder (Box 242, Folder 13)
      - Unidentified: first names only, 1861-1879; 1 folder (Box 242, Folder 14)
  - Documents, 1841-1907; 2 folders
    Contains an insurance policy, indentures, death certificate for Elizabeth Blair Lee, and receipts.
    - Receipts, 1841-1892; 1 folder (Box 243, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous Documents, 1857-1907; 1 folder (Box 243, Folder 2)
  - Photographs, circa 1869; 1 folder (Box 243, Folder 3)
    Contains photographs of Jessie Benton Fremont and her son, Charles (circa 1869).
  - Memorabilia, 1836-1885; 1 folder (Box 243, Folder 4)
    Contains locks of Elizabeth Blair Lee's hair, invitations, and cards.
  - Artifacts, 1843; 1 folder (Box 243, Folder 5)
    Contains a pair of satin dancing slippers, ribbons, a tape measure, a miniature thermometer, and two wooden bobbins.
  - Miscellaneous Material, 1835-1910; 8 folders
    Contains calling cards, recipes, and biographical material regarding the death of Elizabeth Blair Lee, domestic notebooks, notes on Blair genealogy, prescriptions, and some material relating to the Washington City Orphan Asylum.
    - Biographical material relating to the death of Elizabeth Blair Lee, undated; 1 folder (Box 243, Folder 6)
      Included are descriptions of her life in Washington in the 1830s-1860s, as well as her relations with Presidents Jackson, Van Buren, Buchanan, and Lincoln.
    - Calling cards, undated; 1 folder (Box 243, Folder 7)
    - Cookbooks and recipes, 1862-1893; 1 folder (Box 243, Folder 8)
    - Domestic notebooks, 1849-1888; 1 folder (Box 244, Folder 1)
    - Genealogy notes, undated; 1 folder (Box 244, Folder 2)
    - Notes and poems, 1835-1836; 1 folder (Box 244, Folder 3)
    - Prescriptions, 1837-1854; 1 folder (Box 244, Folder 4)
    - Washington City Orphanage Asylum, 1876-1910; 1 folder (Box 244, Folder 5)
  - Printed Matter, 1860-1913; 3 folders
    Contains a cookbook, The Virginia Housewife (1860), by Mary Randolph with handwritten recipes enclosed, as well as miscellaneous clippings, pamphlets, announcements, and advertisements.
    - General, 1866-1890; 1 folder (Box 244, Folder 6)
    - The Virginia Housewife, 1860; 1 folder (Box 244, Folder 7)
    - Clippings, 1862-1913; 1 folder (Box 244, Folder 8)
  - Papers of Others, 1852-1889; 3 folders
    Consists of the papers of Elizabeth "Betty" Blair Comstock, as well as other family and miscellaneous correspondence.
    - Elizabeth "Betty" Blair Comstock, 1852-1857; 1 folder (Box 244, Folder 9)
      Elizabeth "Betty" Blair Comstock was the daughter of Montgomery Blair, and the adopted daughter of Francis Preston Blair and Eliza Violet Gist Blair. Included are letters to her, notices of school awards, and financial accounts.
    - Family Correspondence, 1861-1876; 1 folder (Box 244, Folder 10)
      Contains several letters between Blair family members.
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1866-1889; 1 folder (Box 244, Folder 11)
- Papers of Andrew Alexander Blair, 1855-1874; 4 boxes
  The papers of Andrew Alexander Blair, son of Francis Preston Blair, Jr. (1821-1875), consist of correspondence, miscellaneous material, and papers of others. The correspondence contains primarily letters by family members, especially his mother, Apolline Alexander Blair, written mainly when Blair was a midshipman at the U.S. Naval Academy (1866). Among the papers of others, Samuel W. Very (1846-1919), Blair's roommate at Annapolis, is represented by diaries (1859-1860, 1863), notebooks, correspondence with family members and friends, photographs, and memorabilia, including an autograph album.
  - Correspondence, 1858-1874; 2 boxes (1 partial) 8 folders
    Consists of the correspondence of Andrew Alexander Blair, including family correspondence, naval correspondence, and letters written by Andrew Alexander Blair to Apolline Alexander Blair, Francis Preston Blair, Eliza Violet Gist Blair, and Samuel Phillips Lee.
    Arranged into Letters to Blair and Letters from Blair.
    - Letters to Blair, 1858-1867; 1 box 7 folders
      Contains letters to Blair by members of his family, especially his mother, Apolline Alexander Blair, and including letters by his grandfather, Francis Preston Blair, father, Francis Preston Blair, Jr., uncle, Samuel Phillips Lee, and cousin, Blair Lee, as well as letters by friends and miscellaneous naval personnel.
      - By Family, 1861-1866; 1 box
        - Abraham, George M.: 2 ALsS, 1864; 1 folder (Box 245, Folder 1)
        - Alexander, Eveline "Evy", 1863-1864; 2 folders
          - Alexander, Eveline "Evy", 2 ALsS, 1864; 1 folder (Box 245, Folder 2)
          - Alexander, Eveline "Evy", 4 ALsS, 1863; 1 folder (Box 245, Folder 3)
        - Alexander, M. M.: 7 ALsS, 1863-1865; 1 folder (Box 245, Folder 4)
        - Blair, Apolline Alexander, undated; 4 folders (Box 245, Folder 5-8)
        - Blair, Christine (1852-): 2 ALsS, 1864-1865; 1 folder (Box 245, Folder 9)
        - Blair, Francis Preston, Jr. (1821-1875): 4 ALsS, 1864-1865; 1 folder (Box 245, Folder 10)
        - Blair, Francis Preston III (1856- ): 2 ALsS, 1864; 1866; 1 folder (Box 245, Folder 11)
        - Blair, James L. (1854-1904): 13 ALsS, 1864-1866; 1 folder (Box 245, Folder 12)
        - Blair, Mary Elizabeth Woodbury ("Minna," Mrs. Montgomery Blair), 1821-1887: 8 ALsS, 1863; 1 folder (Box 245, Folder 13)
        - Blair, Violet (1848-1833): ALsS, 1866; 1 folder (Box 245, Folder 14)
        - Dick, M. M.: 5 ALsS, 1864-1865; 1 folder (Box 245, Folder 15)
        - Lee, Blair (1857-1944): ANS (draft), undated; 1 folder (Box 245, Folder 16)
        - Lee, Samuel Phillips (1812-1897): 2 ALsS, 1861-1863; 1 folder (Box 245, Folder 17)
        - Palmer, N. F., Jr.: 12 ALsS, 1861-1864; 1 folder (Box 245, Folder 18)
      - By Friends, 1858-1867; 6 folders
        - Friends: A-Z, 1858-1867; 1 folder (Box 246, Folder 1)
        - Bradford, Jack: 7 ALsS, 1865-1866; 1 folder (Box 246, Folder 2)
        - Friends: first names, 1863-1866; 1 folder (Box 246, Folder 3)
        - Friends: by initials, 1866; 1 folder (Box 246, Folder 4)
        - "Fletcher", 1862-1864; 1 folder (Box 246, Folder 5)
        - Invitations, 1863-1864; 1 folder (Box 246, Folder 6)
      - Naval Correspondence, 1863-1866; 1 folder (Box 246, Folder 7)
    - Letters by Blair, 1861-1874; 1 box (1 partial) 1 folder
      Contains letters by Blair to the family members noted above as well as to his grandmother, Eliza Violet Gist Blair.
      - Apolline Alexander Blair: 10 ALsS, 1865; 1 folder (Box 246, Folder 8)
      - Francis Preston Blair (1791-1876): ALS, 1863; 1 box (partial) (Box 246)
      - Francis Preston Blair (1821-1875): ALS, 1864; 1 box (partial) (Box 246)
      - Eliza Violet Gist Blair (1733-1877): ALS, 1865; 1 box (partial) (Box 246)
      - Samuel Phillips Lee (1812-1897): 2 ALsS, 1861-1874; 1 box (partial) (Box 246)
  - Miscellaneous Material, 1855-1864; 3 folders
    Contains academic material relating to Blair's tenure at the U.S. Naval Academy (1863- 1866) when it was housed at Newport, Rhode Island, during the Civil War, as well as calling cards, and some printed matter.
    - Calling cards, undated; 1 folder (Box 246, Folder 9)
    - Naval Academy, 1863-1864; 1 folder (Box 246, Folder 10)
    - General material, 1855-1864; 1 folder (Box 246, Folder 11)
  - Papers of Others, 1857-1866; 2 boxes 1 folder
    Consists primarily of family correspondence and the papers of Samuel W. Very, including his diaries, notebooks, correspondence, photographs, drawings, and printed matter.
    Arranged by author of material.
    - Family Correspondence, 1857-1865; 1 folder (Box 246, Folder 12)
      Contains some correspondence of Francis Preston Blair, Jr., as well as letters by others.
    - Samuel W. Very, 1859-1866; 2 boxes
      Contains diaries, notebooks, correspondence, photographs, drawings, memorabilia, miscellaneous material, and printed matter of Very, a rear-admiral, who attended the naval academy (1863-1866) with Andrew Alexander Blair.
      - Diaries and Notebooks, 1859-1863; 1 box
        - Notebooks: naval, undated; 1 folder (Box 247, Folder 1)
        - Notebooks: school, 1863; 1 folder (Box 247, Folder 2)
        - Diaries, 1859-1863; 1 folder (Box 247, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence, 1861-1866; 14 folders
        Consists primarily of letters written to Samuel W. Very.
        - "Mattie": 6 ALsS, 1864-1865; 1 folder (Box 248, Folder 1)
        - Mckey, Frank S.: 7 ALsS, 1863-1865; 1 folder (Box 248, Folder 2)
        - Mckey, Joseph: 5 ALsS, 1863-1865; 1 folder (Box 248, Folder 3)
        - Very, Edward "Ned" W.: 5 ALsS, 1864-1865; 1 folder (Box 248, Folder 4)
        - Very, Mary "Mollie": 7 ALsS, 1864-1866; 1 folder (Box 248, Folder 5)
        - Very, Mary Elizabeth, 1862-1866; 2 folders
          - Very, Mary Elizabeth, 1862-1864; 1 folder (Box 248, Folder 6)
          - Very, Mary Elizabeth, 1865-1866; 1 folder (Box 248, Folder 7)
        - Very, Samuel, Jr.: 11 ALsS, 1863-1866; 1 folder (Box 248, Folder 8)
        - Very, Sarah Williams Mckey: 17 ALsS, 1862-1866; 1 folder (Box 248, Folder 9)
        - Very, Lucy: ALS, 1863; 1 folder (Box 248, Folder 10)
        - Friends, 1861-1866; 1 folder (Box 248, Folder 11)
        - Schools, 1864-1866; 1 folder (Box 248, Folder 12)
        - Business, 1863-1866; 1 folder (Box 248, Folder 13)
        - Letter to "Miss Davol": ALS, 1864; 1 folder (Box 248, Folder 14)
      - Photographs and Drawings, undated; 1 folder (Box 248, Folder 15)
      - Memorabilia, 1860-1866; 1 folder (Box 248, Folder 16)
      - Miscellaneous Material, 1864; 1 folder (Box 248, Folder 17)
      - Printed Matter, 1864-1866; 1 folder (Box 248, Folder 18)
- Papers of Blair Lee, 1740-1946; 1857-1925; 218 boxes (1 partial)
  The papers of Blair Lee, lawyer and U.S. senator, consist of his writings, correspondence, legal files, documents, financial material, miscellaneous material, printed matter, and papers of others. The writings contain essays in literature, philosophy, and politics, and course notebooks in languages, science, the Bible, and other subjects while an undergraduate at Princeton (1876-1880), as well as notes taken at Columbian Law School (1880-1883), and manuscripts of political speeches.
  The correspondence is indicative of the close relationship between Lee and his parents, Elizabeth Blair Lee and Samuel Phillips Lee, as well as the warm family ties he held with the extended Blair and Lee families and later with the Brooke family, the relatives of Anne Clymer Brooke Lee, whom he married in 1891. Of special interest are the letters to Lee written from France by his sons who served as officers in the U.S. army during World War I. The active political role Lee took on a local, county, state, and national level, culminating in his election to the U.S. Senate in 1913 to fill the unexpired term of Isidor Rayner (1850-1912), is reflected in the correspondence which includes letters by William Jennings Bryan (1860-1825), congressman and unsuccessful candidate for president in 1896, 1900, and 1908, President Woodrow Wilson (1856-1924), and John Walter Smith (1845-1925), congressmen and senator from Maryland. The correspondence also includes letters regarding Lee's ill-fated Maryland gubernatorial race (1911) and the presidential election campaign of Woodrow Wilson (1912).
  In addition, there are letters pertaining to Lee's legal and business interests, as well as general correspondence containing letters dealing with Grace Episcopal Church in Silver Spring, recreational clubs such as the Takoma Park Gun Club, Princeton and Ivy Club alumni activities, the administration of Silver Spring Farm, and friends dating back to Lee's youth and Princeton years. The correspondence also contains letterbooks including copies of his letters to family and friends, as well as political, legal, and business letters, and invitations, calling cards, and address books. Among the legal files are papers for cases handled by Lee, such as the Brown and Munsell gun case, the estates of Senator James Beck (1822-1890), Morgan Lester, Francis W. Lusby, Allan McLane (1823-1897), and Thomas W. Wise, as well as a challenge to the will of Judge Joseph Holt (1807-1894), references to some French spoliation claims, and many other miscellaneous cases. The documents and financial matters contain receipts, checkbooks, ledgers, account books, canceled checks, and insurance policies for Lee's farm, real estate holdings, and personal matters.
  His interests encompassed legal, philanthropic, fraternal, and political groups, and the organizational files include correspondence, documents, and miscellaneous material in varying degrees for the District of Columbia Bar Association, the Metropolitan Club, the National Junior Republic, the Society of the Cincinnati in the State of Virginia, the National Mary Washington Association, the Washington City Orphan Asylum, and the Democratic National Publishing Company, primarily for the Silver Knight-Watchman.
  The collection also includes family photographs, juvenilia, and memorabilia relating to Lee's early academic and religious training as well as his years at Princeton and Columbian Law School. There are political, legal, and business papers contained in the miscellaneous material of the collection, as well as blueprints, maps, and architectural renderings. Scrapbooks containing political newspaper clippings and other printed matter concerning Lee's political, legal, and business interests are included in the papers.
  The material in papers of others pertains mainly to Lee's family as represented by his wife, parents, and sons, Edward Brooke Lee and Phillips Blair Lee as well as miscellaneous family members. Also found are the legal papers and correspondence of George H. Lamar (1865-1945) and William H. Lamar (1859-1928), lawyers of Baltimore and Washington, D.C., and correspondence and printed matter of Judge Joseph Holt.
  - Writings and Notes, 1862-1925 June 5; 4 boxes
    Consists of the writings of Blair Lee, including biographical and family writings, Princeton, Columbian Law School, and political writings.
    Arranged by genre of writing.
    - Biographical - Family, 1876-1925 June 5; 3 folders
      Contains a speech by Lee and reminiscences by Elizabeth Blair Lee retold by her son.
      - "A service of great historical interest": announcement of presentation by the Lee family of a choir pew, Washington Memorial Chapel, Valley Forge, PA, 1925 June 5; 1 folder (Box 249, Folder 1)
      - "Doctor Burke, Members of the Lee Family, Ladies and Gentlemen": text of speech written and delivered by Blair Lee, June 5, 1925, at the presentation of a choir pew, Washington Memorial Chapel, 1925 June 5; 1 folder (Box 249, Folder 2)
      - "The most dramatic scene she ever witnessed": reminiscences of Elizabeth Blair Lee retold by Blair Lee, 1876-1880; 1 folder (Box 249, Folder 3)
    - Princeton, 1876-1880; 2 boxes 11 folders
      Contains course essays, miscellaneous speeches, and course notebooks.
      - School Essays, 1878-1880; 4 folders
        - Literature, 1878; 1 folder
          - "Future of the English Language,": AMs, 1878; 1 folder (partial) (Box 249, Folder 4)
          - "Caliban,": AMs, 1878 October 24; 1 folder (partial) (Box 249, Folder 4)
          - "Since First Written the Works of Shakespeare.. .": AMs, 1878; 1 folder (partial) (Box 249, Folder 4)
        - Philosophy, 1880; 1 folder
          - "Supremacy of Ideas": AMs, 1880 May 31; 1 folder (partial) (Box 249, Folder 5)
          - "Self-consciousness": AMs (initialed, June 1, 1880), 1 folder (partial) (Box 249, Folder 5)
        - Politics, 1878-1880 June 7; 1 folder
          - "Instruction,": AMs, 1878 July 4; 1 folder (partial) (Box 249, Folder 6)
          - "The Army,": AMs, 1878 April; 1 folder (partial) (Box 249, Folder 6)
          - "The Causes of Our Present Political Troubles,": AMs, 1878; 1 folder (partial) (Box 249, Folder 6)